bnz.co.nz 2016-06-16

# Your privacy and security - Help and support - BNZ

Our banking systems provide extra security to keep your personal and financial information and account details safe when you are banking online or on a mobile; or using cheques and our range of cards.

Some of our security features use two-step identity identification and others use special techniques developed by us or our providers. We can even identify you, when you call us, using your voice with voice biometrics, which is even more secure than using your fingerprint as a form of ID — and you don’t need to remember a PIN. It is also important that you take steps yourself to keep yourself secure online. There are also a few simple steps you can take when using cheque, card or internet and mobile banking services. We also take the privacy of your personal information seriously and will do everything we can to protect it from being used unlawfully wherever you provide it.

### Report your security issues

If you have any concerns about your BNZ accounts or online security, or you suspect you have responded to a fraudulent email, please call our Customer Solutions Advisors on **0800  275 269** or **+64  4 494 9098** from overseas (international toll charges apply).

## Privacy of your personal information

Wherever you provide personal information about yourself, whether it’s online or in store, we will do everything we can to protect it from being used wrongly.

We follow the privacy provisions as set out in the Privacy Act, which says we can collect information for a lawful purpose. We believe in being honest and upfront with our customers at all times. We’ll only disclose information in accordance with our Standard terms and conditions, or if we are required to by law. Under the Privacy Act, you’re entitled to see and request the correction of any personal information about you held by us. As a new customer, you can choose not to supply this information but we may not be able to accept you as a customer.

### Foreign tax compliance

Overseas and local laws mean New Zealand financial institutions, including BNZ, may have to collect and in some cases report your personal and account information to foreign governments under certain circumstances.

The United States law commonly known as the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) has been implemented in New Zealand by provisions in the Income Tax Act 2007 and the Tax Administration Act 1994 and came into effect on 1 July 2014. FATCA applies to major banks and financial institutions around the world. It requires us to collect and share certain customers’ personal and account information with the New Zealand Inland Revenue, which will share it with the US Internal Revenue Service (IRS).

Our standard terms and conditions encompass our general need to collect and disclose your personal information as we’re required to by local or overseas law. We’ll always try to contact you before we share your information with regulatory authorities.

Find out more about FATCA.

## We protect you online

We have taken steps to make sure that you and your computer are safe when visiting our website and/or using Internet Banking, Internet Banking for Business, and Mobile Banking.

#### You can trust our website

Our website has security certificates (issued by Entrust) which prove to you that our site is genuine, encrypted, and secure, giving you peace of mind that your personal and financial confidential information is protected.  You can check that our site (and any other website you visit) has been authenticated with a security certificate easily in any internet browser you are using.  Proof of the authentication appears in a variety of ways — the address bar or part of the URL may be green (or any other colour depending on your browser) or there will be a padlock symbol next to the address or in some other part of the address bar. Sometimes, you may have to click a similar padlock symbol at the bottom of the browser page to see the certificate.  If you ever go to our website, and you can’t see a sign that the site has a security certificate, please call us on 0800 800 468.

#### We alert you about security issues

We publish security alert messages on the login pages of our Internet banking services if there is any suspicious activity, to let you know what’s happening. We’ll also tell you if there is anything extra you can do to protect your identify and money from the risk of online fraud.

#### You are protected when you use Online Banking and PC Business Banking

When you use our Internet Banking services, you are protected by NetGuard or Mobile NetGuard if you are using the Mobile Banking app, adding an additional layer of security to our other systems and procedures. PC Business Banking also comes with its own robust, customisable online security protection, including options to have multiple users authenticating each other’s transactions and the ability to control what individual users can do within system.

Find out more about:

  * Online Banking security
  * PC Business Banking security
  * NetGuard

#### Things we’ll never ask you to do

We will never change the login process for Internet Banking without telling you first, and we will never ask you to tell us or anyone your password.

## Protect yourself online

There are steps you can take to help keep your computer and your personal and financial information safe when you are banking or doing anything online.

#### Get anti-virus software

You can protect your computer’s hardware and software from internet threats like malware, which includes computer viruses, spyware, trojans, and rootkits, by installing and maintaining reliable and reputable anti-virus (AV) software. These Internet threats often infect computers through compromised websites, email attachments, and affected files from attached devices such as a USB sticks and then corrupt and delete data on your computer and/or use your email account to infect other computers by sending illegal spam emails. If your computer is running really slowly, it might be sign it is infected. To help keep your computer virus-free, make sure:

  * your AV software is configured properly so it doesn’t slow your computer down
  * your AV software is configured to automatically update everyday
  * you schedule a weekly AV scan of your computer. 

### Did you know?

If you are a BNZ Internet Banking customer, you won’t have to worry about Internet threats while you are using Internet Banking online, because NetGuard helps to protect your account(s) against malware.

#### Have a strong password

You should make sure you have strong passwords for all your different Internet accounts, not just your Internet Banking account. This increases your security online and reduces the risk of someone accessing your accounts and taking your personal information.

#### Check the sites you visit

If you are using publicly accessible computers in Internet kiosks or accessing the Internet via free public WiFi, you should check the security certificates on any websites you visit. Also, check the address bar — if it shows “http **s** ://” (instead of “http://) that means the  connection is more secure.

## Get in the know

To keep yourself aware of security issues and how to further keep yourself safe, check out the information on:

  * Phishing
  * Online fraud
  * How to create a strong password
  * Privacy statements
